I'm here with Isabelle Stanton, who is a PhD student at Berkeley,
我旁边这位是伊莎贝尔·斯坦顿 她是加州大学柏克莱分校的博士生
and she works on theory of computation.
她研究计算理论
So what are you working on?
你在做什么研究？
Lately I've been working in computational economics,
最近我一直在研究计算经济学
which is this exciting thing that really Berkeley focuses on,
这是伯克利关注的令人激动人心的事情
so looking at problems that economists face
研究经济学家面临的问题
and see whether or not we can develop algorithms and ways to solve this.
看看是否可以开发算法和方法来解决此问题
So particularly the thing that I've been working on has been computational social choice.
我一直在研究计算的社会选择
Social choice functions are ones that aggregate people's preferences.
社会选择函数集合了人们的偏好
So think about this as a voting mechanism.
把这个当做是投票的机制
Everybody gets to say, "I prefer Candidate A to Candidate B to Candidate C,"
每个人都可以说 我更喜欢候选人 A 而不是候选人 B 或 C
and then we take everyone's votes and we output some kind of winner.
我们统计每个人的投票 输出获胜者
And you'd really like this winner to be the one most people prefer or something.
你真的希望这个获胜者是大多数人更喜欢的
The problem that I've been specifically looking at is that back in the 1970s
我专门研究了 早在70年代
Gibbard and Satterthwaite showed that for any kind of reasonable voting mechanism
吉伯德和萨特表明 任何一种合理的投票机制
it's going to be susceptible to manipulation.
都容易受到操控
So is this like when someone doesn't vote for their preferred candidate
是不是这好比 有人不为首选候选人投票
because they think it's going to be better for them
因为他们认为
if they vote for sort of the more popular, less preferred candidate? >>Exactly.
如果他们投票给更受欢迎的自己的第二候选人 这对他们来说更好？确实如此
So if you knew that your favorite person was the underdog
所以 如果你知道你最喜欢的候选人是弱者
and there was no way, you might change your vote
他没有出路 你可能改变你的投票
so that way your second favorite person would be the one that's elected.
这样 你的第二候选人将当选
We've been specifically looking at Binary Cup voting protocols,
我们已专门研究了二进制杯投票协议
which are familiar to people as single elimination tournaments.
这是人们所熟知的单淘汰锦标赛
So how could someone manipulate a tournament like this?
人们如何操作这样的锦标赛呢？
The tournament organizer is allowed to pick the seeding of the players,
赛事组织者被允许挑选种子球员
and that's the bracket, that's in each round who plays against who.
这就是淘汰赛的比赛对手安排 即每一轮中谁和谁是对手
For example, I can show you over here on the computer.
例如 我在这里可以用计算机向你展示
Here on this slide we have actually the Women's World Cup.
这张幻灯片写的是女足世界杯
The seeding is this picking of Germany versus Japan, Sweden versus Australia.
种子队是在日本与德国、瑞典与澳大利亚中挑选
If I wanted something else to happen,
如果想要不同的结果
maybe I could have picked a different initial seeding here,
也许我可能会选择不同的初始种子队
like maybe I have Sweden play England,
也许我可以选择瑞典与英国队比赛
and that would end up with a different result out of the tournament.
最终的比赛结果将会不一样
Let's go over a simple example.
让我们看一个简单的例子
Everyone is familiar with the game rock, paper, scissors.
大家都很熟悉石头剪刀布的游戏
And in computer science we like things to be a power of 2,
在计算机科学中 我们喜欢2的幂
so let's add in hand grenade so that way we have 4 players.
让我们添加手榴弹 这样我们就有4个球员
So we've got rock, paper, scissors, hand grenade.
所以我们已经有石头、剪刀、布和手榴弹
Now we can look at 2 different tournament brackets that have different winners.
现在我们可以看看有不同赢家的2种淘汰赛结构
So if we have rock, hand grenade, paper, scissors,
如果我们有石头和手榴弹 布和剪刀
first rock wins this match-up and then scissors wins here
第一次 石头赢得比赛 这里 剪刀赢得比赛
and then rock wins the total bracket.
然后 石头夺总冠
If, on the other hand, we have rock face paper and scissors face hand grenade,
另一方面 我们有石头和布 剪刀和手榴弹
then paper knocks out rock, hand grenade still wins,
然后布赢了石头 手榴弹仍然是赢家
and hand grenade is the final winner.
手榴弹是最后的赢家
So the tournament manipulation problem is to figure out if there's a bracket
所以锦标赛操纵问题是要找出是否有比赛对手安排
so that your favorite player wins, like this,
这样 你最喜欢的队就可以获胜 像这样的
given information about the match outcomes.
鉴于有关比赛结果的信息
I'm not sure if this explains how the US lost the Women's World Cup,
我不知道 这是否可以解释 美国队在女足世界杯中落败的原因
but we'll leave that as an open problem.
但这是一个公开问题